<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[UFOdev]]></title>
  <link href="http://MikeUFO.github.com/MikeUFO/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://MikeUFO.github.com/MikeUFO/"/>
  <updated>2012-05-31T15:01:02-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://MikeUFO.github.com/MikeUFO/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[MikeUFO]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Learn Up]]></title>
    <link href="http://MikeUFO.github.com/MikeUFO/blog/2012/05/25/learn-up/"/>
    <updated>2012-05-25T11:49:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://MikeUFO.github.com/MikeUFO/blog/2012/05/25/learn-up</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Lately I&#8217;ve been having a recurring conversation about learning, namely, how humans do it and what&#8217;s the process for learning something. This mostly keeps coming up because I speak more than one language. Not really all that unusual, but to some people who are trying to pick up a second language I might have just as easily walked to the moon and back. I&#8217;m not at all an expert on the science of learning but I figured my blog would be a good place to share what I do know about it. And maybe I&#8217;ll have a <a href="http://learncodethehardway.org/">Learn Spanish the Hard Way</a> project or something at the end to post to github. We&#8217;ll see.<!-- more --></p>

<h2>Learning Me Some</h2>

<p>I enjoy learning languages(human and computer) mostly because I had a bomb ass high school French teacher, Mrs. Plowden. She was old school and would&#8217;ve thrown you out of a window if that would help you learn French. When I began being taught by her I was a decent student but not exceptional by anyone&#8217;s definition. I&#8217;m the dumb kid in a family of honor students and over achievers so you get the idea. I excelled in her class though. I didn&#8217;t really have an aptitude for it, she just drilled the basics into me until I knew that shit cold. After 3 years of high school French with her I had the grammar, culture, and accent on lock. By the time I went to the real Paris it was like I had already been there a few times. On that trip I used everything that I had learned from her, even the stuff that I thought was stupid. Kinda cool.</p>

<p>When I got to college, I took the foreign language placement tests and placed out of French completely. I still took it anyway&#8230;easy A. Anyway, what&#8217;s important is I have a system for learning that worked for me then and that I continue using to this day. I&#8217;ve learned new languages and things not language related, but always in the same way: repeat that shit until I know it&#8230;cold.</p>

<h2>Learning You Some</h2>

<p>You&#8217;re excited and feeling giddy because you just decided you want to learn Spanish or French or Ruby or C# or underwater fire prevention or one of the millions of other things you might want to learn. You can&#8217;t wait to get started but figuring out where to begin is only half the battle. Now you have to do something. The good news is that you can learn it even if you think you can&#8217;t. The bad, but not too bad, news is that <a href="http://www.brainrules.net">every brain really is wired differently</a>. How long it takes and the method that works for you may take some time for you to figure out. Still, the basics apply to anyone: make a schedule that you can follow everyday, know how far you want to go, and, most importantly, start now. Just doing those 3 things will get you really close to where you want to be and when you need to go further you can add some specialized techniques that will push you to the next level.</p>

<h2>Learning Us Some</h2>

<p>I think by the end of the next few posts you&#8217;ll have a plan that will help you on your way to learning anything and we&#8217;ll both have a handy reference that we can use when we need it. I&#8217;ll try to include lot&#8217;s of Sciencey stuff and references with 6d charts so you&#8217;ll know the information is legit. Some parts you&#8217;ll agree with and others you may not but what I hope you take from this is an idea that learning is simple once you have the process down. First up: Part 1 &#8211; You Can&#8217;t Get There from Here</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Octopressing]]></title>
    <link href="http://MikeUFO.github.com/MikeUFO/blog/2012/05/01/octopressing/"/>
    <updated>2012-05-01T09:15:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://MikeUFO.github.com/MikeUFO/blog/2012/05/01/octopressing</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2>Welcome</h2>

<p>Welcome to UFOdev! My blog is finally online after many, many months of messing around and getting distracted. This time around I knew I had to get it done or it wasn&#8217;t going to ever be done. All Mary Lou in &#8216;84 on y&#8217;all, I came through in the clutch and got this mofo up and going.  Now&#8230;only 1000 more things to go.<!-- more --></p>

<h2>Another Blog? WTF!</h2>

<p>I know, I know the world wants another blog like I want to be eaten by lions. This is just one more blog among the kazillions of them already online, but this one happens to belong to me. That probably makes you care even less, but I won&#8217;t let that stop me from adding to the blog count. Still, drop in once in a while and see what&#8217;s here. Maybe you&#8217;ll find something that you can rant and rave for. This is a mostly PG blog about the things I&#8217;m interested in: Arsenal, code, and technology. Mostly code and technology, but posts about AFC will come up every now and again. When Arsenal lose, the rating on this blog will most certainly go to R. If you have any suggestions for things you want to see. Let me know about it.</p>

<h2>&#8216;Pressing It</h2>

<p>If you haven&#8217;t noticed already I&#8217;m using Octopress for this blog and hosting it at my github repo, just like all the kool kidz. And guess what? This shit is pretty fucking sweet! I&#8217;ve always wanted to give Octopress a try and now that I have, it looks like I&#8217;m going to stick with it, for a while at least. The other good thing about using Octopress is that I get to play around with some ruby code which is always nice. I started learning Ruby and Rails about a year ago and now that I know a little bit, I like digging into projects and looking through the code. I don&#8217;t get to do a lot of Ruby or GIT on my day job, so this makes it easy for me to have something I can hack on and keep learning. The Octopress setup is pretty straight forward and I highly recommend it for anyone that wants a blog or just a static website. It&#8217;s also a good way to get started with GIT and GIThub if you&#8217;ve been thinking about it.</p>

<p>Well enough for introductions. Once again welcome! It&#8217;s a celebration, enjoy yourself!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
